Cristian Serrano

Product Designer

With 15+ years of experience as a designer, I enjoy simplifying complex challenges and setting design teams up for success. I focus on product design and systems, with a strong background in visual and UI design.

I've led design implementation across multiple platforms and devices, bridging Design and Engineering while leveraging research and user feedback to drive user-centered and business-empowering solutions.

- cristianserrano.ar
- in linkedin.com/in/cristianserrano

Skills

Human

- 🤞 Personal: Critical and analytical thinking, Ownership, Curiosity, Fast learning, Problem solving.
- Inter-personal: Communication, Empathy, Collaboration, Feedback, Conflict resolution, Stakeholder management.

Technical

- Product: Needs analysis, Competitive analysis, Strategy, Canvas, Prioritization, MVP definition, Roadmap.
- X UX: User interviews, Personas, Empathy map, Journey map, Heuristics, Information architecture, User flows, Wireframes, Interaction design, UX writing, Lo-fi prototyping.
- 🧪 **UI:** Benchmark, Moodboard, Stylesheet, Component libraries, Hi-fi mockups and prototypes, Motion design, Conversational, Handoffs.
- 📽 Other: Mobile platforms, Accessibility, Responsiveness, Lean, Agile, Design thinking, Product Management, User testing, Design systems, DesignOps, Editorial design, Branding.

Tools

- of Ideation: Figjam, Miro, Mural, Whiteboard.
- 📏 **Design:** Figma, Sketch, Adobe CC, Pen & paper.
- Prototype and Handoff: Design tools, inVision, Zeplin, HTML/CSS, and a bit
- Productivity: Google Workspace, Microsoft 365, Atlassian Suite, Slack, Zoom, Loom, Git.

Languages

- Spanish: Native
- English: Fluent
- **German:** Beginner

Education

UX/UI Design Sep 2020 - Aug 2021 Acámica

Visual Communication Design Feb 2006 - Mar 2013

National University of La Plata

Hobbies

- Traveling and exploring new things Mentoring other designers
- Photography and Videography
- Storytelling in any media
- Playing musical instruments
- Passionate about technology
- Sustainability

Experience

Senior Product Designer, Design Systems Manager Dec 2021 - Present

Kaia Health

Kaia Health is an Al health-tech that offers digital programs to help people with musculoskeletal difficulties (including chronic back, hip, and knee pain) and COPD:

- I was brought to Kaia to help fix inconsistencies in flows and screens as they scale.
- Kickstarted Kaia's Kinetic Design System after interviewing key stakeholders and auditing the state of Kaia's brand, apps and websites.
- Managed a team of 4 developers (2 Android, 2 iOS) and a senior designer to build and maintain the DS.
- Systematized and built 100% of foundational elements, and the 20% of components that solved 80% of our needs, as well as standardizing high-level patterns.
- KDS empowered our production teams to reach their product goals even after 2 RIFs.
- Eventually moved to a Lead/DesignOps role, being in charge of tooling and processes, as well as hiring and mentoring new designers.

Senior Product Designer Nov 2020 - Nov 2021

Google @Globant

Worked on Area 120's (Google's incubator) Orion Wi-Fi, a connectivity offload service:

- Worked on 2 dashboard (cellular and wi-fi admins) and a companion app (to self test the wi-fi network quality).
- Conducted user interviews and leveraged insights into the first market version.
- · Focused on data visualization and customization options for cellular networks admins, as well as venue/wi-fi admins.
- Ideated and built features to help onboard corporate customers, helping make the service viable.
- Launched the first real time marketplace for wireless connectivity.

Senior Product Designer Mar 2020 - Nov 2020

Google @Globant

Due to my strength as an end-to-end hybrid designer, i got rotated to work with Google:

- Worked with Google My Business, on a new service called Small Business Advisors.
- · Worked with high-level definitions of the service and impacted not only on the experience and the visuals of the service, but on the value proposition for the business side.
- Leveraged Google Standards, their custom implementation of Google Material.
- Launched and MVP in Q2, and a second iteration in Q3 with great feedback.

Senior User Experience and Visual Designer Sep 2019 - Feb 2020 Disney @Globant

Worked on migrating FOX Play's Latam streaming platform to Disney's DTCI platform after Disney's acquisition of FOX:

- Focused mostly on the UI bits, coming with design systems experience, for the web, apps, and smart TV experiences.
- Balanced DTCI's limitations with FOX brand needs to provide a simple solution while maintaining brand continuity.

Senior Product Designer, Design System Lead Feb 2018 - Aug 2019

Openbank @Globant

Still on Openbank, I led a team of developers, designers, and analysts to build a React and React native based Design system, Openbank Guidelines:

- Provided a healthy library of components, processes, and documentation to help iterate quickly on new features, and give old features a much needed refresh.
- Empowered Openbank's Design team to quadruple their size. • Acquired valuable experience on the banking, e-commerce, fintech, and insurtech
- industries and I positioned myself as a Design system and DesignOps touchstone within the company.

User Experience and Visual Designer Dec 2017 - May 2018

Openbank @Globant

I joined Globant to learn from a large-scale multidisciplinary team: • Started on Openbank as part of the Insurances team.

- · Ideated and implemented new insurance offerings, with a friendlier wizard approach
- that eventually scaled to older offerings.

UX/UI, Web, Graphic & Visual Designer Jun 2009 - May 2017 Self-employed

Throughout 8 years as a freelancer designer, I had to wear several different hats: • Worked mostly on Branding and Identity, but would work on anything that a brand

- needed to support their message: Photography and Videography, Editorial design, Motion graphics, etc. • Started doing Web design in 2014, and soon after I had my first Product design
 - project working with FocusFreak on their virtual assistant platform, Virtstart.

Teaching Assistant Apr 2007 - Aug 2008 Visual Communication Design, Workshop 1B

I was offered a Teaching Assistant position on the core subject of the VCD career:

• Got the opportunity to help fellow students and understand teaching mechanics.

• Working with people with different backgrounds was a great exercise for empathy.

Graphic Design Intern Sep-Dec 2005 Imprenta Oligraf

• Exploratory internship to understand what Design was all about.

- · Decided to pursue Design as a discipline at University.

Courses

- Designing Influence, by Nielsen Norman Group. Mar 2024
- Product Psychology Masterclass, by Growth.Design. Mar Jun 2023 • Operating Design Systems, by Nathan Curtis. Nov 2022
- Cognitive Psychology and User Experience, by Daniel Mordecki. Apr 2018
- Design Systems Virtual Summit, by UXPin. Feb 2018
- Accio UX, by DevRock School. Aug Sep 2017